A Guide to the Papers of Robert Frost, 1873-1981
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Robert Frost 1873-1981
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6261 through 6261-bi
This collection consists of ca. 1000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was acquired ca. 1960-1997 through multiple gifts of Clifton Waller Barrett, Lesley Frost Francis Ballentine, and Lesley Lee Francis.
Biographical/Historical Information
Robert Lee Frost (born March 26, 1874 in San Francisco, Calif., died January 29, 1963 in Boston Mass.), was one of America's leading 20th-century poets and a four-time winner of the Pulitzer Prize.
The Frost family moved to Massachusetts in 1885, following Frost's father's death. Frost graduated from Lawrence High School in 1892 and entered Dartmouth College, where he remained less than one semester. Frost returned to Massachusetts where he taught school and worked in a mill and as a newspaper reporter. In 1894 he sold "My Butterfly: an Elegy" to The Independent, a New York literary journal. He married Elinor White in 1895. From 1897 to 1899 he attended Harvard College as a special student but left without a degree. Over the next ten years he wrote (but rarely published) poems, operated a farm in Derry, New Hampshire (purchased for him by his paternal grandfather), and supplemented his income by teaching at Derry's Pinkerton Academy.
In 1912, at the age of 38, he sold the farm and used the proceeds to take his family to England, where he could devote himself entirely to writing. His efforts to establish himself and his work were almost immediately successful. A Boy's Will was accepted by a London publisher and brought out in 1913, followed a year later by North of Boston. Favorable reviews on both sides of the Atlantic resulted in American publication of the books by Henry Holt and Company, Frost's primary American publisher, and in the establishing of Frost's transatlantic reputation.
The Frosts returned to the United States in February 1915 and landed in New York City two days after the U.S. publication of North of Boston, the first of his books to be published in America. Sales of that book and of A Boy's Will enabled Frost to buy a farm in Franconia, N.H.; to place new poems in literary periodicals and publish a third book, Mountain Interval (1916); and to embark on a long career of writing, teaching, and lecturing. In 1924 he received a Pulitzer Prize in poetry for New Hampshire (1923). He received the Pulitzer again for Collected Poems (1930), A Further Range (1936), and A Witness Tree (1942). Over the years he received an unprecedented number and range of literary, academic, and public honors.
Scope and Content
The collection contains manuscripts of poetry, plays, addresses, essays, notebook, a workbook, and other writings by Frost. Many are fair copies written for Earle Bernheimer, Clifton Waller Barrett and others. With these are some proof and other publication materials for the Limited Editions Club volume of The Complete Poems of Robert Frost.
Manuscripts by the Frost children include notebooks of poetry and short stories by Lesley, Carol, and Irma Frost, and The Bouquet magazine by the Frost children and English friends.
Manuscripts about Robert Frost include notes or articles by John T. Bartlett, Margaret Bartlett, Elizabeth Jennings, and Dorothy Judd Hall; as well as page proof of Sidney Cox's A Swinger of Birches and a typescript of The constant symbol by Clifton Waller Barrett.
Frost family correspondence includes letters from Robert and Elinor to daughter Lesley Frost Francis, and grandson William Prescott Frost, as well as correspondence of granddaughter Lesley Lee Francis. There are also five letters of Frost's parents William Prescott Frost, Jr. and Isabelle Moodie Frost.
Letters to Earle J. Bernheimer discuss his writing, health, family affairs, and Bernheimer's Frost collection. Letters to Robert S. Hillyer touch on readings, honors, and Hillyer's poetry. Lengthy letters to former student John T. Bartlett discuss family and work. Letters from English friends during World War I mention the English war effort.
Other correspondents include Clifton Waller and Cornelia Barrett, William Stanley Braithwaite, LeBaron R. Briggs, Abbie Farwell Brown, Cyril Clemens, Padraic Colum, Lewis Henry Cohn, Grace Hazard Conkling, Aaron Copland, Clarence R. Decker, George Dillon, Frank D. Fackenthal, Wilfred Wilson Gibson, Vera Harvey, J. J. Lankes, Edward Connery Lathem, John Masefield, Harry Meacham, Harold Monro, Kathleen Morrison, Thomas B. Mosher, Robert S. Newdick, William Jay Smith, R. W. Stallman, Will Orton Tewson, Lawrance R. Thompson, Wade Van Dore, and John Hall Wheelock.
Miscellaneous material includes programs; playbills; invitations; brochures; two pencil drawings by Frost; a painting "The sound of the trees Robert Frost" by E. A. Anderson; reviews; clippings; maps; articles; photographs; and recordings of Robert Frost readings and of his memorial service with narration by Allen Tate.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in three series. Series I, Manuscripts, is arranged in three subseries: Subseries A. Manuscripts by Robert Frost, sub-arranged as Poetry, Plays and Other Writings; Subseries B. Manuscripts by the Frost Children; and Subseries C. Manuscripts by Others about Robert Frost.
Series II, Letters, is arranged in three subseries: Subseries A. Correspondence of Robert Frost, Elinor Frost and the Frost Family; Subseries B. Correspondence of Lesley Frost Ballantine; and, Subseries C. General Correspondence.
Series III, Miscellaneous, includes documents outside the scope of the first two series, printed materials, photographs and recordings.
Contents List
- Series I. Manuscripts
  - Subseries A. Manuscripts by Robert Frost
    - Subseries 1. Poetry by Robert Frost
      - Poem, "Ceasar's Lost Galleys," with autograph note at bottom of last page, n.d.; AMsS, 2 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "Directive," with autograph inscription "To Russell from R. F.", n.d.; AMsS, 2 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "Down to Earth," with autograph notation at bottom of last page, 1953 November 23; AMsS, 3 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, ["Evensong"], n.d.; AMsS (Box 1)
      - Poem, "Fire and Ice", AMsS, 1 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "For Last Columbus Day," with autograph notation, "R. F.'s copy", n.d.; TMsS, 3 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "Geode," inscribed to Earle Bernheimer, 1939 August 17; AMsS, 1 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "The Gift Outright," with autograph revisions and autograph note at bottom, "Written before 1936", ante 1936; TMsS, 1 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "The Gift Outright," with autograph revisions and autograph note at bottom: "My history of the Revolutionary War which was the beginning of the end of colonialism. R. F.", TMsS, 1 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "It Bids Pretty Fair," inscribed to Louis Henry Cohn, n.d.; AMsS (copy), 1 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "Lost in Heaven," with printer's instructions, with one-page ALS [copy], December 15, 1933, [Robert] Frost to Mr. Hazlitt, n.d.; TMsS, 1 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "My Old Uncle", n.d.; AMsS, 1 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "A Nature Note," inscribed "to R. V. Thornton from R. F.", n.d.; AMsS, 1 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "Neither Out Far nor In Deep," [copy made for Louis Dodge], AMsS, 1 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "On Being Shown a Cosmic Ray", n.d.; AMsS, 1 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "On the Inflation of the Currency, 1919", AMs, 1 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "Once by the Pacific," with "The Pans" on verso, with autograph revisions, n.d.; AMs, 2 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "A Restoration," sent to Robert Hillyer, [1932 September 28]; AMsS, 2 p. w/env (Box 1)
      - Poem, "The Road that Lost Its Reason," with autograph notations in margin, n.d.; AMs, 1 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "Stopping by Woods on a Snowy Evening," four lines, in unidentified hand, signed by Robert Frost, AMsS, 1 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "Till the Day Breaks," with autograph note re asterisk in text, [1946]; AMsS, 1 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "Time Out," with autograph revisions, n.d.; AMsS, 1 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "To a Moth Seen in Winter," inscribed "For Russell's collection", ca. 1900; AMsS, 2 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "Two Leading Lights", 1944; AMsS, 1 p.
        With two photoreproductions of the poem and two telegrams used to form Christmas cards by Earle Bernheimer [in Bernheimer file]
      - Poetry, A Boy's Will, collection of 29 poems, with autograph inscription in back to Clifton Waller Barrett, "A few remarks and acknowledgements." Bound, [1948]; AMsS, 33 p.
        "Stars", "Storm Fear", "Wind and Window Flower", "To the Thawing Wind", "Flower-Gathering", "Into My Own", "Ghost House", "My November Guest", "Love and a Question", "A Late Walk", "Rose Pogonias", "Waiting -- Afield at Dusk", "In a Vale", "In Neglect", "The Vantage Point", "Mowing", "Going for Water", "Revelation", "Trial by Existence", "In Equal Sacrifice", "The Tuft of Flowers", "The Spoils of the Dead", "Pan with Us", "Now Close the Windows", "The Demiurge's Laugh", "A Line-storm Song", "October", "My Butterfly", "Reluctance"
      - Poetry, The Steeple Bush, collection of 39 poems, presentation inscription to Earle Bernheimer, March 26, 1947 [in Bernheimer file], AMsS, 13 p.
        "But He Meant It" ["The Broken Drought"], "US 1946 --King's X", "Bursting Rapture", "The Planners", "One Step Backward Taken", "Why Wait for Science", "No Holy Wars for Them", "Etherealizing", "To the Right Person", "We Can Have It Any Size We Please" ["Any Size We Please"], "A Young Birch", "A Mood Apart", "From the Papyrees Prisse", "Something for Hope", "The Spire" ["A Steeple on the House"], "The Night Light", "To an Ancient", "A Rogers Group", "Upsilon Iota Subscript" ["Iota Subscript"], "In the Long Night", "On Making Sure Anything Has Happened" ["On Making Certain Anything Has Happened", "A Wish to Comply", "Astrometaphysical", "A Cliff Dwelling", "Beyond Words", "Innate Helium", "Two Leading Lights", "The Importer" ["An Importer"], "Her Fear" ["The Fear of Man"], "The Ingenuities of Debt", "Bravado", "The Play" [It Bids Pretty Fair"], "A Bed in the Barn", "The Courage to be New", "Skeptic", "On Being Idolized", "The Middleness of the Road", "Haec Fabula Docet", "US 1946 King's X"
      - Poetry, The Steeple Bush, 38 poems, inscription to Earle Bernheimer, March 26, 1948 [in Bernheimer file], AMsS, 33 p.
        "An Unstamped Letter in Our Rural Letter Box", "Blind Individualist" ["Haec Fabula Docet"], "To an Ancient", "On Being Idolized", "To the Right Person", "The Middleness of the Road", "Skeptic", "On Our Deciding to Have Our Universe Smaller" ["Any Size We Please"], "A Young Birch", "Ten-Thirty A. M." (Not in published volume), "The Courage to be New", "The Fear of God", "Why Wait for Science", "No Holy Wars" ["No Holy Wars for Them"], "The Planners", ["A Steeple on the House"], ["Innate Helium"], "Etherealizing", "The Importer" ["An Importer"], "The Cliff Dwelling" ["A Cliff Dwelling"], "Astrometaphysical", "Were I in Trouble with Night Tonight" ["Were I in Trouble"], "A Case for Jefferson", "Two Leading Lights", "Bravado", "It Bids Fair" ["It Bids Pretty Fair"], "Beyond Words", "The Night Light", "The Ingenuities of Debt", "The Common Danger" or "Fear of Man" [The Fear of Man"], "Upsilon Iota Subscript" ["Iota Subscript"], "Nature I Loved and Next to Nature Art" or "Lucretius versus the Lake Poets", "A Mood Apart", "A Wish to Comply", "The Broken Drought", "In the Long Night", "On Making Sure Anything Has Happened" ["On Making Certain Anything Has Happened"]
      - A Witness Tree, containing 27 poems, inscribed to Earle Bernheimer, November 20, 1942 [in Bernheimer file], AMsS, 25 p.
        "The Silken Tent", "A Cloud-Shadow", "Come In", "Give All to Time" ["I Could Give All to Time"], "Carpe Diem", "To a Moth Seen in Winter", "Happiness Makes Up in Height for What It Lacks in Length", "Time Out", "Triple Plate" ["Triple Bronze"], "Wilfull Homing", "It is Almost the Year Two Thousand", "Telescopic --A Loose Mountain" ["A Loose Mountain (Telescopic)"], "To a Young Wretch" ["To a Young Wretch (Boethian)"], "The Literate Farmer and the Planet Venus --A Dated Popular Science Medley", "Never Again Would Birds Be the Same", "All Revelation", "A Considerable Speck" ["A Considerable Speck (Microscopic)"], "The Gift Outright", "An Admirer of the Flag" ["Not of School Age"], ["The Secret Sits"], ["An Answer"], ["A Question"], "On the Difficulty of Keeping Up in Sympathy" ["On Our Sympathy with the Under Dog"], ["Assurance", "The Most of It", "Beech", "Sycamore"
      - Poetry, A Witness Tree, collection of 43 poems, presented to Earle Bernheimer, November 20, 1942 [in Bernheimer file], TMsS, 74 p.
        "To a Moth Seen in Winter", "A Considerable Speck (Microscopic)", "The Lost Follower", "For the Fall of Nineteen Thirty Eight" ["November"], "The Rabbit Hunter", "A Loose Mountain (Telescopic)", "It is Almost the Year Two Thousand", "In a Poem", "On Our Sympathy with the Under Dog", "Boeotion", ["The Secret Sits"], "An Equalizer", ["Assurance"], ["A Question"], ["An Answer"], "Trespass", "A Nature Note", "Of the Stones of the Place", "Not of School Age", "A Serious Step Lightly Taken", "The Literate Farmer and the Planet Venus", "Beech", "Sycamore", "The Silken Tent", "All Revelations", "Happiness Makes Up in Height for What It Lacks in Length", "Come In", "I Could Give All to Time", "Carpe Diem", "The Discovery of the Madeiras --A Rhyme of Hackluyt", "The Wind and the Rain", "The Most of It", "Never Again Would Birds Song Be the Same", "The Subverted Flower", "Willfull Homing", "A Cloud Shadow", "The Quest of the Purple-Fringed", "The Gift Outright", "Triple Bronze", "Our Hold on the Planet", "To a Young Wretch" ["To a Young Wretch (Boethian)"], "The Lesson for Today", "Time Out",
      - Poetry, [Untitled] "New Poems Toward the Next Book," collection of 16 poems, presented to Earle Bernheimeron February 21, 1941, AMsS, 16 p.
        "The Silken Tent", "Come In", "Geode", "Triple Plate", "To a Moth Seen in Winter", "Wilfull Homing", "A Considerable Speck-Microscopic", "A Cloud Shadow", "Happiness Makes Up in Height for What It "Lacks in Length", "A Loose Mountain-Telescopic", "Trespass", "A Serious Step Lightly Taken", "In Praise of Waste", "To a Young Wretch", ["The Gift Outright"], ["The Secret Sits"],
      - Poetry, [Untitled], [1951]; AMsS, 25 p.
        Collection of 26 poems in blue paper cover, with autograph inscription by K[athleen] M[orrison]: "This is a special selection of poems made by Mr. Frost for Mr. Barrett..."
        "Never Again Would Birds Song Be the Same", "Against Thinking", "Mowing", "The Line-gang", "Closed for Good", "Dust of Snow", "The Tuft of Flowers", "The Mountain", "Blue-butterfly Day", "Reluctance", "My November Guest", "Hyla Brook", "November", "A Blue Ribbon at Amesbury", "Astrometaphysical", "Why Wait for Science", "For Columbus Day", "Choose Something Like a Star", "Tree at My Window", "Wanton Waste", "Good- bye and Keep Cold", "Something for Hope", "A Young Birch", "A Leaf Treader", "The Lost Follower", "The Gift Outright",
      - Poem, "A Heart in Charge" with autograph comment to [John T. Bartlett] by Robert Frost at end, AMsS, 2 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "The Lost Followers," with autograph note to Mr. Linscott from Robert Frost beneath the poem, 1936 June 28; AMsS, 1 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "The Lure of the West" written for [John T. Bartlett and Margaret Bartlett], AMsS, 2 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "Good Relief", n.d.; AMsS, 1 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "The Peaceful Shepherd," with "Lodge" after title crossed out, n.d.; AMs, 1 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "On Going Unnoticed, Nature's Neglect", n.d.; AMs, 1 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "Sand Dunes", 1926 December; AMsS, 1 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "The woods are lovely dark and deep" [from his poem, "Stopping by Woods on a Snowy Evening"]. On small card, AMsS, 1 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "A Dream of Julius Caesar", 1891 May; TMs, 2 p. (Box 1)
        Poem published originally in the Lawrence, Massachusetts High School Bulletin
      - Poem, "La Noche Triste. Tenochtitlan" and "The Flight", 1892; TMs, 3 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "Song of the Wave", 1890 May; TMs (carbon), 1 p. (Box 1)
      - Poetry in notebook includes "A Record Strike," 3 p., "A Stone Missive," 2 p., "The Truth of It," 1 p., and "Two Tramps in Mud Time" (3 p.), 1933; AMsS, 9 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "Three Holocausts in Two Poems" ("Fire and Ice" and U. S. 1946 -- King's X"), text by Robert Frost and music by Harris Lindenfield, 1971; AMs (copy), 2 sets (Box 1)
      - Poetry, A Boy's Will, corrected first "revise," cut unbound proof, published by Spottiswoode and Co., London, 1913 January 20; TMs, 50 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "A Blue Ribbon at Amesbury," author's galley proof, with autograph corrections, published in A Further Range, 1936; TMs, 1 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "A Record Stride," author's page proof, with autograph note, "All correct, thanks, R. F.," published in A Further Range, 1936; TMs, 1 p. (Box 1)
      - Poetry, Come In and Other Poems, 1943; Page Proof (Box 1)
        Selection, biographical introduction, and commentary by Louis Untermeyer, illustrated by John O'Hara Cosgrave, II, and published by Henry Holt and Company, inscribed by Robert Frost to Earle Bernheimer. Also inscribed proofs of the title page and a Cosgrave illustration.
      - Poem, "Realism", [ca. 1912]; AMs, 1 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, untitled, beginning "In winter in the woods alone," last poem in In the Clearing, with explanation of origin of this copy, 1962; AMsS (copy), 1 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "A Patch of Old Snow," inscribed "For Margaret Haley Carpenter/Winter in England 1912", [1958]; AMsS, 1 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "The Courage to Be New," inscribed "For William Stanley Braithwaite", [1958]; AMsS, 1 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "Acquainted with the night" n.d., TMs, 1 p. (Box 1)
        Removed from Papers of the Virginia Quarterly Review, RG-24/3/1.571
      - Poem, "Astrometaphysical" n.d., TMsS, 1 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "Directive" 1945, TMsS, 2 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "The figure in the doorway" n.d., AMsS, 1 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "The gift outright" n.d., TMsS, 1 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "In time of cloudburst" n.d., AMsS, 1 p. (Box 2)
      - Poem, "Iris by night" [1936], AMsS, 2 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "The middleness of the road" n.d., TMsS, 1 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "The silken tent" n.d., TMs, 1 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "Time out" n.d., TMsS, 1 p. (Box 1)
      - Poem, "To a moth seen in winter" n.d., TMsS, 1 p. (Box 1)
      - Galley proof, Three poems by Robert Frost n.d. (Box 1)
        "Directive", "The middleness of the road", "Astrometaphysical." With correction by Frost. Signed "R. Frost o.k." Removed from Papers of the Virginia Quarterly Review, RG-24/3/1.571
      - Galley proof, "The silken tent" n.d. (Box 1)
      - Galley proof, Three poems by Robert Frost n.d. (Box 1)
        "The gift outright", "To a moth seen in winter", "Time out." Removed from Papers of the Virginia Quarterly Review, RG-24/3/1.571
    - Subseries 2. Plays by Robert Frost
      - The Guardeen, first version of the play, presented to Earle Bernheimer, January 12, 1942 [in black slipcase], n.d.; AMsS, 66 p.
      - The Guardeen, second version of the play, presented to Earle Bernheimer, January 12, 1942 [in black slipcase], AMsS, 54 p.
      - In an Art-Factory, with autograph commentary by Robert Frost on the play and when it was written, signed "R. F. Ripton June 22, 1951" [in notebook], AMsS, 25 p. (Box 2)
      - A Masque of Mercy, play, with inscription to Earle Bernheimer [in slipcase], 1948 March 26; AMsS, 40 p.
      - A Masque of Mercy, play, with inscription to Earle Bernheimer [in slipcase], 1944 May 26; AMsS, 25 p.
      - A Masque of Reason, 1945 February; Page Proof, 30 p. (Box 2)
      - A Masque of Reason, 1945; Galley Proof, 21 p. (Box 2)
      - A Masque of Reason, Printer's trial titles, 1945; Proofs (Box 2)
    - Subseries 3. Other Writings by Robert Frost
      - Autobiography of William Prescott Frost, Jr., with autograph note at top of first page, "Please return to Robert Frost, Franconia, N. H.", 1872 June 24; AMsS, 10 p. (Box 2)
      - The Constant Symbol, with autograph revisions, an introductory essay written for the Modern Library 1946 edition of The Poems of Robert Frost [in notebook], 1946 August; AMs, 11 p. (Box 2)
      - "The Death of the Hired Man," preface to, for Whit Burnett High School textbook, with autograph notations, 1945 October 26; TMsS, 1 p. (Box 2)
      - Sketch of Ernest Silver, head of Pinkerton Academy, Derry, New Hampshire, with autograph revisions and notation, 1946 May 16; TMsS, 1 p. (Box 2)
      - "John L. Sullivan Enters Heaven," together with TLS, August 19, 1942, Louis Untermeyer to Earle Bernheimerabout the manuscript, n.d.; AMsS, 1 p. (Box 2)
      - Workbook of Robert Frost, in part children's stories, kept in Derry, New Hampshire, [ca. 1906]; AMsS, 44 p. (Box 2)
      - Layout material relating to Bruce Rogers' design for The Complete Poems of Robert Frost for the Limited Editions Club, ca. 1950; 6 items (Box 2)
        Includes: Proof, 2 l., ca. 1950, Galley proof of Frost's introduction "The Figure a Poem Makes" for The Complete Poems of Robert Frost with printer's instructions by Rogers; Proof, ca. 1950, Proof of the half-title to Volume I of; Proof, ca. 1950, Hand proof of title to Volume I of The Complete Poems of Robert Frost; Layout, ca. 1950, Layout for contents page of The Complete Poems of Robert Frost; Layout, ca. 1950, Pencilled layout for colophon by Rogers for The Complete Poems of Robert Frost; TMs, 1 p., ca. 1950, Typescript, with pencilled corrections, of copyright notice for The Complete Poems of Robert Frost
      - "The Constant Symbol," with foreward by C[lifton] Waller Barrett, 1946 July; TMs (carbon), 10 p. (Box 2)
      - "What Became of New England?" an Oberlin College commencement address by Robert Frost, with autograph revisions by Robert Newdick, 1937 June 8; TMs (carbon), 5 p. (Box 2)
      - "Petra and Its Surroundings", 1891 December; TMs, 2 p. (Box 2)
        Essay published originally in the Lawrence, Massachusetts High School Bulletin.
      - "Editorial", 1892 May; TMs, 1 p. (Box 2)
      - "A Monument to After-Thought Unveiled", 1892 June; TMs, 2 p. (Box 2)
      - Preface for a book by Hervey Allen, ca. 1940; AMs, 2 p. (Box 2)
      - Notes re poems and writings kept by Robert Frost, AMs, 4 p. (Box 2)
      - A small black notebook kept by Robert Frost during his residence in England, containing ca. two hundred separate entries of ideas, observations, random thoughts, epigrams, meditations, and descriptions, and one complete and unpublished Frost poem, 1912-1915; AMs, [118] p. (Box 2)
      - The Letters of Robert Frost to Louis Untermeyer, bound uncorrected galley proofs, published by Holt, Rinehart and Winston, Inc., New York, 1963; TMs, 293 p. (Box 2)
      - Ideas for poetry or lecture notes kept by Robert Frost, ca. 1935; AMsS, 2 p. (Box 2)
      - Untitled text for Frost's introduction to a broadcast of his poems, n.y. March. 27; TMs, 1 p. (Box 2)
        6261-bi
  - Subseries B. Manuscripts by Frost children
    - Introduction by Lesley Frost to Joan St. Crane's book, n.d.; TMsS, 3 p. (Box 2)
    - Pages from a child's notebook containing short stories: "Camping," "After It Has Rained," "The Last Flowers of the Year," "My First Remembrance of a Birthday Party," "Burning a Paper," "A Discovery," "A Trilling [sic] Moment," and columns of whist scores, [ca. 1910?]; AMs, 34 p. (Box 2)
    - Notebook of short stories by Lesley Frost entitled "Desk" and kept while the Frost family lived in Plymouth, New Hampshire, [ca. 1912?]; AMsS, 28 p. (Box 2)